Amarylis Riehn

Nashville, TN | amaryliscreates@gmail.com | (615) 674-8309

Portfolio: www.amaryliscreates.com | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/amaryliscreates

SUMMARY
UX / UI Designer with a curious, detailed, and human-centric approach to problem-solving. A background with over five years in Graphic Design before transitioning to UX/UI Design work in the health and wellness industry Experienced in effective team culture, communication, and multi-faceted roles.
SKILLS & TOOLS
Key Skills (UX) User Experience Design, (UI) User Interface Design, Graphic / Visual Design, Frontence Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), Al User Design, Research, Prototyping, Wireframing, Usability Testing
 Collaborating and effectively communicating with stakeholders, clients, and cross-functional teams. Motivating and encouraging approach to giving and receiving feedback. A kind human with a generous attitude.
Tools Figma, AI (ChatGTP 4), Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Excel
PROJECTS
Foodguides.com UX, UI, Frontend Dev Mark Cuban Companies Health 10/2023 - present
 Brought a User Experience and mobile-first approach to the next iteration of an MVP health & nutrition website. Through UX Research, established baseline metrics and discovered user problems and opportunities, including discoverability of content and a need for guidance in their health journey. Developed a user-centric product and brand strategy for current (and future) iterations while honoring business needs. Includes new features, AI user design, brand identity, and improved usability.
AllWell Research, UX, UI CareerFoundry Healthcare 09/2022 - 04/2023
 Created a responsive web application for family caregivers by engaging in user research to investigate and define the problem in order to design for core needs before testing a prototype and iterating on a solution. Included features that cut down on time spent in the caregiver's role by identifying a core need for collaboration and data sharing specific to caring for multiple people and partnering in care.
UX/UI Portfolio Frontend Development, UX, UI CareerFoundry 05/2023 - 07/2023
 Enhanced my ability to collaborate and communicate effectively with development teams by expanding my understanding of the Frontend Development aspect of product design.

Resume 1 of 2

• Coded (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript), user-tested, W3C validated, cross-browser checked, and launched a responsive website for a UX professional. Implemented a mobile-first design strategy that was expanded for

tablet and desktop users using Media Queries in the CSS and a 12-column grid.

Amarylis Riehn

Nashville, TN | amaryliscreates@gmail.com | (615) 674-8309

Portfolio: www.amaryliscreates.com | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/amaryliscreates

WORK EXPERIENCE
UX/UI Designer, Frontend Dev Foodguides (Mark Cuban Companies) Contract 10/23 - present
 Improved usability, evolved the service, and helped more people, by bringing a user experience and mobile-first approach to the next iteration of the health and wellness website. Developed strategy and user design of an AI feature while integrating new AI tools into the project's workflow. Managed end-to-end ownership of the design while working with a cross-functional team.
Graphic Designer & Admin Jeff Roberts Agency Hendersonville, TN Talent Booking 09/2019 - 09/2021
 Multi-faceted role with shifting priorities in a fast-paced environment. Optimized company workflow by managing, troubleshooting, and evolving custom software and web products. Increased company revenue by researching and analyzing data for targeted sales efforts and digital marketing.
Graphic Designer Freelance Design Services Business, Individual, and Non-Profit 01/2010 - 09/2019
 Interpreted core human needs and designed effective solutions by listening and empathizing with clients. Branded marketing materials, organizational design, interior/exterior design, and illustrated mockups/comps.
Director Guelph COC Guelph, ON, Canada Non-Profit 01/2015 - 1/2019
 As part of the leadership team, launched a non-profit organization to work alongside and serve community needs in the world's most multicultural and diverse area. Achieved by conducting extensive research, defining mission and vision, and designing professional marketing materials crucial to fundraising 500K+ projects.
Graphic Designer IndoorDIRECT Dallas, TX Digital Media 01/2009 - 07/2011
 As a part of the creative team, developed and maintained brand identities and digital and print materials. Contributed to shareholder value in the acquisition of new restaurant partnerships by designing solutions that effectively enhanced the visual communication of sales presentations.
EDUCATION
UX Design, Certificate CareerFoundry Online 2023
Frontend Development for Designers, Certificate CareerFoundry Online 2023
Graphic Design, Associates of Fine Arts The Art Institute Dallas, TX 2008

Resume 2 of 2